<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text NurAnnisa</string>
    <string name="article_title">Blackpink: What You Need to Know About K-pop Biggest Girl Group</string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">2020 might be the year Blackpink rose to the top of the US pop charts, but this is not the group first time in the spotlight</string>
    <string name="article" translatable="false">       The four-member South Korean girl band — who get their name from the mixture of tough "black"
        and flirty "pink" of songs — have been global superstars since the release of their June 2016 single "Boombayah."
        \n
        \n
        <b>Why are they called Blackpink?</b>
        \n
        Formed by YG Entertainment under the famous K-pop trainee system in South Korea, the members auditioned with the entertainment agency to become students or trainees with the hope of one day making their debut as a recording artist. When Blackpink debuted, their label YG Entertainment said the name intends to convey that the group embodies more than beauty — theres a toughness, too.
        "The meaning of BLACKPINK aims to contradict the common perception of the color pink," the statement read. "Pink is commonly used to portray prettiness, but BLACKPINK actually means to say that 'Pretty isn't everything.' It also symbolizes that they are a team that encompasses not only beauty, but also great talent."
        \n
        \n
        <b>How is Blackpink different from other K-pop groups?</b>
        Between their debut in 2016 and the 2020 release of The Album, Blackpink released fewer than 22 songs, all singles. Despite the small discography, the groups glam look and fun choreography were quickly replicated by other K-pop groups and fans in their social media videos.
        The biggest part of Blackpinks popularity lies in their songs, which talk about independence and vulnerability, bilingual lyrics, and undeniable stage presence. Blackpink is also known for the styling of their videos, otherwise referred to as concepts for each song. Where some K-pop videos might have two or three concepts in their music videos, Blackpink will often have five or six completely different concepts (complete with different hair colors and clothing) featured in their video.
        https://people.com/music/blackpink-what-you-need-to-know-about-kpops-biggest-girl-group/
    </string>
</resources>